<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thug R Life</title>
    <link>http://thug-r.life/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thug R Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://thug-r.life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun Math Problems</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-10-02-fun-math-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-10-02-fun-math-problems/</guid>
      <description>Meme Me Up, Scotty!Every now and then on Twitter or Facebook there’s a math problem posted which challenges users to get the right answer. They’re almost always based on order of operations and the reason most people get them wrong is because they don’t remember that elementary rule. It’s hard to blame most people since a lot of math that’s used day to day doesn’t require order of operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bucket List</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-09-01-bucket-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-09-01-bucket-list/</guid>
      <description>Bucket ListMost people end up having a list of things they’d like to do in their life before they ‘kick the bucket’. Often this is made up of big events - a foreign trip, some daredevil adventure. But sometimes that list is a bunch of little things.
RI’ve published a package on CRAN - readOffice - which was designed to enable the importing of text from modern Microsoft Word and PowerPoint files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>purrr Tricks with All Subset Regression</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-24-purrr-tricks-with-all-subset-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-24-purrr-tricks-with-all-subset-regression/</guid>
      <description>All Subsets RegressionWhat is all subsets regression? It’s a technique for model building which involves taking a set of independent variables \(X_1..i\) and regressing them in sets of \(k\), where \(k\) is in \(\{1,2,\dots,i\}\), against the response variable \(Y\). The ‘all’ part of ‘all subsets’ means it’s every combination of \(X_{1..i}\) being drawn \(k\) at a time.
But…why?You’re probably familiar with forward, backward or stepwise model building where terms are added (or removed) from a model one at a time while attempting to maximize or minimize some ‘goodness’ criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Twitter Updates</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-12-automatic-twitter-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-12-automatic-twitter-updates/</guid>
      <description>Automatic Twitter UpdatesOne of my goals with this site is to have as much as possible to automatic. Because it’s a static site, each time I write a post I have to copy all the files (new and updated) to the hosting location so you, the illustrious reader, can enjoy the content I create. Then, I need to promote it. This involves the laborious process of switching to my pinned Chrome tab with Twitter open and writing a tweet remember to paste in a link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legislate by Executive Order</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-10-legislate-by-executive-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-10-legislate-by-executive-order/</guid>
      <description>Executive Orders in the USAFrom Wikipedia:
Executive orders are orders issued by United States Presidents and directed towards officers and agencies of the U.S. federal government. Executive orders have the full force of law, based on the authority derived from statute or the Constitution itself. The ability to make such orders is also based on express or implied Acts of Congress that delegate to the President some degree of discretionary power (delegated legislation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making this Blog</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-08-making-the-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-08-making-the-blog/</guid>
      <description>blogdown magicI made this blog using the magic of blogdown which is a framework that joins together a few technologies to make ‘static websites’
RMarkdownHugoRMarkdownRMarkdown is an interface from R to markdown which is a way of marking up a text document with formating so other tools can convert it from a text file to a pretty format (PDF, Word, etc.) It’s a great way of documenting your code by having your narrative right next to the code that generated the insights/results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Mark Ewing. I&amp;rsquo;m just some guy who currently lives in the northeast part of Tennessee, just barely too far from Asheville, NC to drink Wicked Weed beer every weekend. I work for a big company doing a bunch of stuff and often that stuff involves R. I love R. I mean, not in a creepy way, yet most people still find it creepy. I first learned R in a linear algebra class in college back in 2006 and used it until I finished my masters degree in Applied Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theta Joins in R</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-06-fuzzy-joining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2017-08-06-fuzzy-joining/</guid>
      <description>Theta JoinsCommon Joins
If you’re like me, you’re looking at that diagram wondering what the heck is a ‘theta’ join?! Well, that’s the formal name for a ‘fuzzy’ join. In fact, you can read about all the different join types in this StackOverflow answer.
An equi join is the most common kind of join because it leverages keys in your data source which are essential in a SQL environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Your First Spark Cluster</title>
      <link>http://thug-r.life/post/2016-03-20-installing-your-first-spark-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thug-r.life/post/2016-03-20-installing-your-first-spark-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Installing your first spark clusterSo, if you’re like me you’ve been using a lot of traditional tools for data science/analytics/whatever you want to call it. R is great, it’s flexible, it’s powerful but it’s slow and memory constrained. At work I’ve got a VM with 16Gb and one call can increase it. At home I’ve got an 8 Gb machine and honestly, it works fine for what I do here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>