<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thug R Life</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thug R Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Mark Ewing. I&amp;rsquo;m just some guy who currently lives in the northeast part of Tennessee, just barely too far from Asheville, NC to drink Wicked Weed beer every weekend. I work for a big company doing a bunch of stuff and often that stuff involves R. I love R. I mean, not in a creepy way, yet most people still find it creepy. I first learned R in a linear algebra class in college back in 2006 and used it until I finished my masters degree in Applied Statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theta Joins in R</title>
      <link>/post/2017-08-06-fuzzy-joining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-08-06-fuzzy-joining/</guid>
      <description>Theta JoinsCommon Joins
If you’re like me, you’re looking at that diagram wondering what the heck is a ‘theta’ join?! Well, that’s the formal name for a ‘fuzzy’ join. In fact, you can read about all the different join types in this StackOverflow answer.
An equi join is the most common kind of join because it leverages keys in your data source which are essential in a SQL environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Your First Spark Cluster</title>
      <link>/post/2016-03-20-installing-your-first-spark-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-03-20-installing-your-first-spark-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Installing your first spark clusterSo, if you’re like me you’ve been using a lot of traditional tools for data science/analytics/whatever you want to call it. R is great, it’s flexible, it’s powerful but it’s slow and memory constrained. At work I’ve got a VM with 16Gb and one call can increase it. At home I’ve got an 8 Gb machine and honestly, it works fine for what I do here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>